Guide to the Lee P. Brown Papers, 1954-2013 MS 509
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Lee P. Brown professional papers
1954-2013
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Brown, Lee. P
MS 509
112.5 Linear Feet (113 boxes)
This collection contains the professional papers of Dr. Lee P. Brown. The papers reflect his professional career as Mayor of Houston (1998-2004), Director of the White House Office of National Drug Control Policy (1993-1995), New York City Police Commissioner (1990-1992), Police Chief of Houston, Texas (1982-1990), Public Safety Commissioner of Atlanta, Georgia (1978-1982), and Professor and Scholar at Rice University. Also included in the collection are newsclips, photographs, awards and honors.
Biographical Note
Dr. Lee Patrick Brown was born in the small town of Wewoka, Oklahoma on October 4, 1937. When Dr. Brown was five years old, he and his family, including six brothers, moved to California. As a high school athlete, Dr. Brown earned a scholarship to play football for Fresno State University, where he graduated with a Bachelor's degree in Criminology. He then went on to earn a Masters in Sociology from San Jose State University in 1964, a Masters in Criminology from the University of California at Berkeley in 1968, and a Doctorate in Criminology from the University of California at Berkeley in 1970.
Dr. Brown began his prominent career in law enforcement in 1960 as a patrolman in San Jose, California. After eight years in that capacity, he moved to Portland, Oregon and established the Department of Administration of Justice at Portland State University. In 1972, he joined Howard University in Washington, D.C., becoming Associate Director of the Institute for Urban Affairs and Research. He held the academic rank of Professor of Public Administration and Director of Criminal Justice Programs. He then returned to Portland in 1975 to serve as sheriff of Multnomah County. In 1976, he was appointed Director of Justice Services, a department comprised of all the county's criminal justice agencies. Dr. Brown has also served as New York City Police Commissioner from 1990-92, as Police Chief of Houston, Texas from 1982-90, and also as Public Safety Commissioner of Atlanta, Georgia from 1978-82.
In June 1993, Dr. Brown was unanimously confirmed as the Director of the White House Office of National Drug Control Policy (ONDCP) during the Clinton Presidency. He served in that Cabinet-level position as the "Drug Czar" from 1993 until January 1996. Following his service in the ONDCP, Dr. Brown joined the Faculty at Rice University as a Radoslav A. Tsanoff Professor of Public Affairs in the Department of Sociology as well as a Scholar in the James A. Baker III Institute for Public Policy. Prior to his service in the ONDCP, Dr. Brown also served as a Distinguished Professor at Texas Southern University and Director of the University's Black Male Initiative Program.
In 1997, Dr. Brown became the first African American to ever be elected as Mayor of the City of Houston. He served consecutive terms from 1998-2004, and presided over a very prosperous six-year period in Houston's history. Under his leadership, the City of Houston invested in extensive infrastructure, advanced its affirmative action program, installed programs in City libraries to provide access to the Internet; built the state-of-the-art Houston Emergency Communications Center; implemented e-government, and opened new parks. In 2005, Dr. Brown became Chairman and CEO of Brown Group International, a consulting corporation.
The recipient of numerous awards over the years, Dr. Brown was named Father of the Year by the National Father's Day Committee in 1991, and in 1992 he was awarded the Cartier Pasha Award by Cartier, International. He was also inducted into the national Forum for Black Public Administrators Hall of Fame in 1994 and the Gallup Hall of Fame by Gallup, Inc. in 1993. Dr. Brown was also named to Who's Who in America in 2004. The author of many papers and articles on police management, community policing, crime, the criminal justice system and narcotics, Dr. Brown is also co-author of the book Police and Society: An Environment for Collaboration and Confrontation. He is also a past President of the International Association of Chiefs of Police and is involved in a number of professional and community organizations.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the professional papers of Dr. Lee P. Brown. The papers reflect his professional career as Mayor of Houston (1998-2004), Director of the White House Office of National Drug Control Policy (1993-1995), New York City Police Commissioner (1990-1992), Police Chief of Houston, Texas (1982-1990), and as Public Safety Commissioner of Atlanta, Georgia (1978-1982). Brown also served at Rice University as Herbert Autrey Visiting Scholar at the School of Social Sciences, Radaslav A. Tsanoff Professor of Public Affairs in the Department of Sociology, and as a scholar at the James A. Baker III Institute for Public Policy. Also included in the collection are newsclips, photographs, awards and honors.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Restricted items in this collection are marked in the inventory. To obtain permission, please contact Dr. Lee P. Brown.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
This material was donated by Dr. Lee P. Brown, 2005, 2006, 2013, and 2015.
Index Terms
Subjects
African Americans; Community policing; Law and legislation; African American mayors; Mayors; Municipal government; Police-community relations; Police chiefs; Politics and government
Places
Georgia -- Atlanta; New York (State), New York; Texas -- Houston
Subjects (Persons)
Brown, Lee. P; Whitmire, Kathryn J.; Dinkins, David N.
- Series I: College and San Jose Police Department, 1955-1968, 42815
  - Subseries A: General, 42856
    - Biography/Resume, 1967; 212226 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Certificates, 1965-1967; 212227 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1968; 212228 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Development of a Police-Community Relations Program grant, 1967; 212230 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Drug Program, 1967; 212231 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Governor's Conference on Youth, 1965; 212235 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Graduate Fellowship Program for Law Enforcement Officers, 1969; 212236 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - High School Commencement Program, 1955; 212238 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Information Concerning the San Jose Police Department, 1967; 212239 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Institute for Social Inventions, 1968; 212240 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Law Training Bulletin, 1968; 212245 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Memoranda, 1961; 212246 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - News Clippings, 1957; 212247 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - News Clippings, 1965; 212250 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - News Clippings, 1966-1968; 212252 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Office Planning Program, 1965; 212258 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Peace Officers' Association of the State of California: Proceedings, 1964-1965; 212259 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Planning and Development of a Police-Community Relations Program grant application, 1966; 212260 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Police Advisory Subcommittee, 1966; 212264 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Police and Community Relations Coordinator job description, ca. 1967; 212265 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Police-Community Relations Area Committee, ca. 1967; 212266 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Police-Community Relations: A Critique on Issues That Tend to Divide Us" - John A. Buggs, 1965; 212268 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Police-Community Relations Conference, 1967; 212269 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Police-Community Relations - a suggested course outline, 1967; 212270 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Police Ombudsman, 1966-1968; 212271 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Police Review Board research, 1965; 212272 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Police Seminar, 1966; 212274 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Political View Point Questionnaire, 1968; 212277 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Public Relations Committee, 1963-1964; 212278 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - "Report on the Conference on Crime", 1967; 212280 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - San Jose Police Department Annual Report, 1966-1968; 212286 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - San Jose State College, 1967; 212291 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - San Jose State College Campus Protests, 1968; 212292 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - San Jose State College Racial Unrest, 1967-1968; 212294 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Service Division, 1967; 212295 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Special Salary Increases for Patrolmen Without Similar recommendations for Firemen-Disparity, 1966; 212303 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Subseries B: Articles and Papers, 212208
    - "Adoption", 1960; 212307 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - "An Analysis of Human Relations Problems and Needs in San Jose, California", ca. 1967; 212308 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "Application of System Analysis to Law Enforcement, 1968; 212310 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - "Armed Robbery", 1967; 212311 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - "Black Muslims and the Police", 1965; 212316 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - "Black Musims and Police Officers", ca. 1967; 212317 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Black Muslim term paper, 1966; 212318 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - "The Challenge of Crime in a Free Society" - San Jose Police Department's Response, ca. 1967; 212320 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - "The Chronic Alcoholic Offender and the San Jose Police Department", 1966; 212321 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Community Relations Unit in San Jose term paper, 1966; 212329 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - "A Course in Police Community Relations", 1967; 212330 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - "Court v. Police", 1966; 212331 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - "Cultural Approach to Crime", 1962; 212332 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - "Development of a Police-Community Relations Program", 1967; 212333 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - "The Development of a Police-Community Relations Program: An Assessment of the San Jose Project" - Master's Thesis, 1968; 212337 (Box 1, Folder 51-52)
    - Dissertation prospectus, ca. 1967; 212346 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - "Dynamic Police-Community Relations at Work", 1968; 212347 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - "Education of Minority Groups", 1961; 212348 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - "Emile Durkheim", 1963; 212349 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Essay on Malcolm X, ca. 1966; 212350 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - "A Fair Employment Practice Policy for Local Law Enforcement Agencies", 1968; 212351 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - "Handling Complaints Against the Police", 1968; 212352 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - "The Ombudsman", 1967; 212467 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Police Community Relations: The San Jose Project", 1967; 212469 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Police Review Board", 1966; 212472 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Police Review Boards: An Historical and Critical Analysis", 1966; 212475 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Policing of the Chicago Convention", 1968; 212478 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Problems Facing Law Enforcement Agencies, 1968; 212485 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "Public Relations in the Junior College System", 1964; 212486 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "San Jose v. Police Review Board", 1966; 212487 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - "Social and Crime Problems in the Downtown Sector", 1967; 212488 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Sul-Si-Puedes and Little Egypt: The Development of a Police-Community Relations Program in San Jose", 1966; 212489 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "Survey of Relationships Between the Police Department and the Black Community in Pasco, Washington", 1968; 212562 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "Thoughts on Police-Community Relations", 1967; 212563 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "An Unforeseen Problem Resulting from College Educated Policemen", 1966; 212564 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Subseries C: Speeches, 212209
    - Law Enforcement's Role in Democratic Society, ca. 1965; 212565 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Law Enforcement's Role - Lecture at San Jose State University, ca. 1965; 212566 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Police Community Relations, ca. 1965; 212567 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Prayer Garden Church, ca. 1965; 212568 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "Support Your Local Police", 1966-08-02; 212569 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "Police Review Boards", 1966-08-24; 212570 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "Community Support for the Police", 1966-08-30; 212571 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Address to United California Republicans, 1966-10-14; 212572 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Address to Menlo Oaks School, 1966-11-10; 212573 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Youth Crime, ca. 1966; 212574 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - "Police and Community Relations", 1967-01-24; 212575 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - "Police-Community Relations", 1967-03-14; 212576 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Address to CCPCA, 1967-04-14; 212577 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Series II: Portland State University Professor, 1968-1972, 42782
  - Subseries A: General, 42814
    - Academy of Criminal Justice Sciences, 1969-1972; 212578 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Afro-American Historical Society, 1971; 212579 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Afro-American Patrolmen's League, 1971; 212580 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Albina Multi-Service Center, 1971; 212581 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1970; 212582 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - American Society of Criminology, 1971-1972; 212583 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "Anatomy of the Police: A Case for Community Control", 1971; 212584 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Appointment book, 1971; 212585 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Appointment book (contains notes and letters), 1972; 212586 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Arizona State Plan, 1972; 212587 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Bachelor of Science Degree in Administration of Justice, ca. 1970; 212588 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Biography/Resume, 1970; 212589 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - "Blacks in the State of Oregon: 1788-1972: A Bibliography", 1971; 212590 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Black Policemen Research Project Proposal, 1970-1971; 212591 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Black Professionals in Higher Education, 1971; 212592 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Black Power, ca. 1972; 212593 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Black Studies Center, 1969; 212594 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Black Studies Coordinating Council, 1971-1972; 212595 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Black Studies Program, 1968-1970; 212598 (Box 2, Folder 45-46)
    - Black Student Union, 1969; 212600 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Board of Police Standards and Training, 1970-1972; 212601 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - California Highway Patrol Academy, 1971; 212602 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Center for Criminal Justice Agency Organization and Minority Employment Opportunities, 1971-1972; 212603 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Chapman, Samuel G., 1969-1971; 212604 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Citizens Civil Service Comprehensive Study Committee, 1972; 212605 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Citizens Civil Service - Comprehensive Study Commission, 1972; 212606 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Civil Disorders Program, 1970-1971; 212607 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Clark, Donald E., 1969-1971; 212608 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Club Uhuru, 1969-1970; 212609 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Columbia Region Association of Governments: Family Crisis Project, 1972; 212610 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Columbia Region Association of Governments Subcommittees, 1969-1972; 212611 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Columbia Region Association of Governments Law Enforcement Committee, 1969-1972; 212613 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Committee on Law Enforcement - League of Women Voters, 1967-1972; 212614 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Community Advising, 1969-1971; 212615 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Community Relations Service, 1969-1971; 212616 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Community Youth Responsibility Program proposal, 1971; 212617 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Comprehensive Criminal Justice Grant Proposal, 1971; 212618 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Conferences, 1970-1972; 212619 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Cooperative Center for Crime Research and Evaluation, 1971; 212620 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Corrections in Oregon: The View from the Administrator's Office", 1970; 212621 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1972; 212622 (Box 3, Folder 12-15)
    - Correspondence with Congress Members, 1970-1971; 212626 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Council of Police Societies, 1970; 212627 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Crime Insurance Grading System grant, 1972; 212628 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "Criminal Justice Educational Programs: Where Are the Black Colleges?", ca. 1971; 212629 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Crime Reduction Impact Program, 1972; 212630 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
    - Criminal and Social Justice Coordinating Committee, 1972; 212632 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - The Danforth Foundation, 1970-1971; 212633 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Department grants, 1966-1972; 212634 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Development of Conflict Management Capabilities in the University grant proposal, 1971; 212635 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Discharge House, 1971; 212636 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - "Equal Justice for All", 1972; 212637 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Eugene Police Department, 1971; 212638 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Evaluation of Police-Community Relations Program Abstract, 1968; 212639 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Germann, A. C., 1968-1972; 212640 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Goodyear Publishing Company, 1971-1972; 212641 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Grand Jury Investigation into Student Incident at Portland State University, 1970; 212642 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Grant and Program Proposals, 1969-1972; 212643 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Grants, 1972; 212644 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Grants Pending, 1971; 212645 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Guest Editorials, 1970; 212704 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Gun Control, 1969-1970; 212705 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - High Crime Impact Task Force, 1972; 212706 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "Historiography of Blacks in Oregon: An Assessment", ca. 1970; 212707 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Housing Authority, 1969-1970; 212708 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Institute for Public Affairs Research Un-Conference, 1971; 212709 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - International Association of Chiefs of Police, 1970-1971; 212710 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Jailing in Multnomah Country--A Time to Change, 1970; 212711 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Joint Commission on Correctional Manpower and Training, 1968-1969; 212712 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Joint Conference on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, 1972; 212713 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lambda Alpha Epsilon, ca. 1970; 212714 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Law Enforcement 302, 1971; 212715 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Law Enforcement and Higher Education, 1968-1971; 212716 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration, 1969-1971; 212717 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration Civil Disorder Conference, 1971; 212718 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Law Enforcement Association on Professional Standards, Education and Ethical Practice, 1971; 212719 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Law Enforcement Council, 1969-1972; 212720 (Box 4, Folder 17-20)
    - Law Enforcement Council grant, 1971; 212724 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Law Enforcement Council Informational Bulletin, 1969-1971; 212725 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Law Enforcement Task Force, 1968; 212726 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - LEAA - Omaha Conference, 1972; 212727 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - LEAF Newsletter, 1970-971; 212728 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - League of Oregon Cities, 1971; 212729 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Mailing lists, 1969-1971; 212730 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. Day, 1971; 212731 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. Scholarship Fund, 1970-1972; 212732 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Metropolitan Study Commission, 1969-1972; 212733 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Metroscene, 1968-1969; 212734 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Minority Recruitment - Albany, NY, 1971; 212735 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Minority Recruitment - Baton Rouge, LA, 1972; 212736 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Minority Recruitment - Connecticut State Police, 1972; 212737 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Minority Recruitment for Police Careers in Norristown, PA Police Department, 1972; 212738 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Minority Recruitment - Ohio Penitentiary System, 1972; 212739 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Model Cities Program, 1968; 212740 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Multnomah County Department of Public Safety, 1969-1972; 212741 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Multnomah County Minority Employment, 1971; 212742 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Multnomah County Probation and Parole, 1972; 212743 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Multnomah County Recruit Training Academy, 1970; 212744 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - National Advising Commission on Criminal Justice, 1972; 212745 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - The National Black Political Convention, 1972; 212746 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The National Center on Police and Community Relations, 1968; 212747 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence, 1968; 212748 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1968-1969; 212749 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - National Corrections Academy, 1972; 212750 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - National District Attorneys' Association, 1971-1972; 212751 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - National Institute on Crime and Delinquency, 1972; 212752 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - National Urban Coalition, 1970; 212753 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - NDDC News, 1971-1972; 212754 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - New Orleans Civil Disorders Conference, 1970; 212755 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - News Clippings, 1969-1972; 212756 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Notes, ca. 1970; 212757 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - The Occupational States of the Negro Worker in the Portland Area, 1969; 212758 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Office of Independent Study, 1969-1972; 212759 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Oklahoma State University Drug Seminar, 1972; 212760 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Ombudsman for Portland Government: A Fresh Look, 1972; 212761 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Omnibus Crime Control Bill, 1968; 212762 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Operation Neighborhood, 1971; 212763 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - The Oregon Black Agenda, 1972; 212764 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Oregon Black Caucus, 1971-1972; 212765 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Oregon Department of Human Resources, 1971-1972; 212766 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Plays, ca. 1970; 212767 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - People for Portland, 1970; 212768 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Police Community Relations, 1970-1972; 212769 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Police-Community Relations Evaluation Project, ca. 1968; 212770 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Police-Community Relations grant, 1969; 212771 (Box 5, Folder 31-33)
    - Police-Community Relations - St. Louis, ca. 1968; 212774 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - The Police-Community Relations Unit summary, 1971; 212775 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Police Foundation, 1970-1971; 212776 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Police Human Relations Training - Buffalo Police Academy, 1972; 212777 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Police-Prosecutor Conference, 1972; 212778 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Police Service Internship Project, ca. 1969; 212779 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Portland City Club Bulletin: Report on Law Enforcement in the City of Portland, 1968; 212780 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Portland City Club Bulletin: Report on Racial Justice in Portland, 1968; 212781 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Portland City Council - Human Relations Committee (photograph), 1970; 212782 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Portland Police Academy - Introduction to the Criminal Justice System, 1971; 212783 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Portland Police Association, 1971; 212784 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Portland Police Bureau, 1969-1972; 212785 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Portland Police Fact Finding Committee, 1969; 212786 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Portland's Police: The Public's View, 1968; 212787 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Proposed Crime Prevention Package for Multnomah County, ca. 1970; 212788 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - "Proposed Insurance Industry Answer to the Crime Crisis", 1971; 212789 (Box 5, Folder 49)